All right. We've gone over some ways of coming up
好的 我们已经学习了
with high level concepts for our metrics.
想出指标高级概念的一些方法
What issues do you run into when you go to actually compute that?
在实际的计算过程中 你遇到了哪些问题？
>> So, what we have so far is really a high level concept for a metric.
我们目前所拥有的是一个指标的高级概念
To move from that to a fully realized definition, there are two main steps.
要将其从一个高级概念变成一个认识充分的定义 有两个主要步骤
The first step is to fully define exactly what data
第一是完全准确地定义
we're going to look at to actually compute the metric.
在实际的指标计算过程中 我们要查看哪些数据
This can be something as simple as which events do I count in my numerator and
这和我使用分子和分母计算
my denominator.
事件一样简单
It can also be questions like am I going to filter the data at all
也可能会遇到问题 如我应该完全筛选这些数据
to remove robots or spam or things along those lines.
将自动操作或垃圾邮件或进程中的事物清除掉吗
And the second step is given those events, how do I summarize my metric?
第二步是对于这些事件 我如何概括我的指标？
Am I computing an average, am I computing a median?
我是在计算一个平均数 还是计算一个中位数？
We'll look at some very simple summer statistics plus
我们来看一些非常简单的和
also some much more complicated ones.
一些非常复杂的夏季统计数据
Now the reality is that as you're going through these steps what you're really
现在 事实是通过这些步骤
doing is you're building intuition about your metric, and about your data and
你实际上要做的是建立关于指标、数据
about your systems.
和系统的直觉
The mark of a really good analyst is whether or
一个好的分析师的标志是
not you understand what changes in your data and
你是否理解数据和指标中的变更
in your metrics, you're system can and can't produce, right?
系统能不能产生 对吧？
So, as an example, I know that if I see a 10% change in click-through rate,
举个例子 我知道如果我看到点击率增长或降低10%
that is wholly unrealistic.
这是完全不现实的
And realistically I probably have a bug in my experiment
说明我的实验中可能存在一个 bug
as opposed to a real true change that led to a 10% change in click through.
因为实际更改导致点击率出现 10% 的变更
That's just utterly unrealistic.
这是完全不现实的
>> Okay, so how would you actually go about doing this?
好 你如何处理？
Say, for example, click through probability from lesson one.
例如 第一课中讲到的点击概率
How would we compute that?
我们如何计算？
>> Well, we have to first decide,
我们首先要判断
given the events that we observe, which ones were actually going to count for
我们观察的事件中 哪些对这些指标有价值
those metrics and how we're going to combine them.
我们如何将它们结合在一起
So, as an example, even for click-through probability,
因此 比如 点击概率
there's probably a few different ways to compute it.
可能有很多不同的方式来计算
One is to count total number of clicks and total of number of page views and
一个是数点击总量和网页浏览总量
just divide total clicks divided by the total page views.
然后用点击总量除以网页浏览总量
Now, we can do a more nuanced version of that as well.
现在 我们可以换个更细致的办法
So there's something called a cookie which is an anonymous identifier for
有一种叫做 cookie 的东西 是用户的
a user.
匿名标识符
It's not really a user but we can, we like to pretend.
实际上不是一个真正的用户 但我们通常假设它是个用户
And what we can do instead is say, did a cookie visit the site, and then,
我们能做的是看看 cookie 是否有访问这个网站 然后
given that a cookie visited, did they click or not?
如果 cookie 访问过这个网站 他们是否会点击？
Now, these different metrics, you know, one's a rate and one's a probability,
现在 这些不同的指标 你知道 一个是比率 一个是概率
they have different semantic meanings, but they also impact the act,
它们具有不同的语义 也会影响
the actual implementation of metric as well as things like the variability,
指标的实际执行和变化性
which we'll talk about a little bit later.
我们在后边会谈到
>> So you also have to worry about a bunch of other detailed things
因此 你不必担心会碰到的
that come up.
其他一些细节问题
So, for example, if you have a page load, and then no click, but
例如 如果你加载了一个页面 但没有点击
then a day later the same cookie comes back, loads the page, waits 15 minutes,
一天以后 同一 cookie 再次出现 加载页面 等了 15 分钟
and then clicks.
然后单击
Is 15 minutes too long?
15 分钟很长吗？
Is the day too long?
一天很长吗？
Do you consider them all being associated with the same record?
你认为它们是相互关联的 属于同一记录么？
There's a lot of these little things that you have to look at.
有很多小的事情需要注意
And depending how much data you have, you may want to plot your data
根据你拥有多少数据 你可能想将一天的数据绘制成图
over the course of a day, look at evening, you know weekday effects.
观察晚上的情况 你知道有工作日效应
Look at the week, maybe even look at the minute or the hour,
观察一周的情况 甚至可能查看具体的分钟或小时
where things are happening.
事情在哪发生
So, you have to ask questions such as,
因此 你必须问这类问题
what happens if someone arrives at your website at 11:50 p.m.
比如如果有人在晚上 11:50 访问网站
And then clicks at 12:01 a.m.
凌晨 12:01 点击你的网站会发生什么情况
Now do you count that as being part of the first day's data?
你将其作为第一天的数据进行统计？
Do you completely separate the two events?
还是将两个事件完全分开？
Or do you count it as part of the second day's data?
还是将其作为第二天的数据进行统计？
And although those events in aggregate can be pretty small,
虽然这些事件总的来说都是小事
if you actually plot your data over the course of a day,
如果你将一天的数据绘制成图
you will see this big dip around midnight.
你会看到半夜的时候会有一个大倾角
>> I've totally seen that before.
我之前看到过
Now, what's interesting is that you have to also consider the technology that's
现在 我感兴趣的是在你计算这些事件时
used when you're actually capturing the events.
必须考虑所使用的技术
So, as an example, JavaScript pings, which send a 204 request,
例如 JavaScript pings 发送 204 请求
are one of the most common ways of actually capturing clicks.
是捕获点击率最常用的方式之一
Now, the issue is that certain browsers, for example,
现在 问题是某些浏览器 例如
very old browsers, don't, don't implement JavaScript at all.
非常旧的浏览器 根本不执行 JavaScript
And then other browsers, you know, so, for example IE versus Safari,
其他浏览器 比如 大家熟悉的 IE、Safari
will have different failure rates on that JavaScript ping back.
在执行 JavaScript ping 时可能会产生不同的失效率
And so what can happen is that as you look at different browsers or
因此 查看不同的浏览器或不同的平台时
different platforms, you'll actually get very different click-through rates.
你会得到迥然不同的点击率
And it's not because the actual click-through rates are different, but
不是因为实际的点击率不同
it's because the technology that you use in order to gather the clicks
而是由于你用于采集点击量的技术
is actually different.
不同
And so in those cases you have to really work with your engineering team
在这几种情况下 你必须和你的工程组一起协作
to understand all of those nuances, understand when you have a real
以明白所有这些细微差别 明白什么时候是
difference, versus the difference through the underlying technology.
真正的差异 和由于技术产生的差异
>> Wow, who have guessed it's so much trouble to count clicks correctly.
哇 谁能想到正确计算点击量会碰到这么多的麻烦